Okay, so let's get
into the system for
writing intros. And you've
got two options here.
Option one, you just
write yourself using the
framework I've given you
in the video planner
section and the checklist.
And you start by
following the intro structure
that you've learned. So
the hook, the problem
or result, the setup,
and the transition. And
then what you do
is you just run
your script through this
checklist. Does it match
what the thumbnail and
title promised? Does the
hook create curiosity in
under five seconds? Have
you poked a relatable
problem or result? Did
you clearly tell the
viewer what they'll get?
Did you show why
you're credible? Did you
smoothly transition into the
first point? Is the
intro under 30 seconds?
Under 15 is ideal.
And then once you've
written it, what you
want to do is
head over to intro
bot in the custom
AI and say, this
is my title. And
you write your title.
And then you say,
can you give me
feedback on this intro?
And what intro bot
is going to do
is it's going to
predict your viewers' expectations.
Like you can see
here, based on the
title, it's going to
check if your intro
hit those expectations. It's
going to give you
feedback based on the
checklist. And it's going
to offer a, rewritten
version of your intro.
Now, the next step
after this is you
take that intro and
you put it into
guardrails and you say,
can you give me
feedback on this intro?
And I know this
feels like another step,
but check this out.
Guardrails is going to
make sure the intro
is positioned towards those
three key problems that
we are building our
entire channel around that
your viewers care about.
It's also going to
suggest credibility lines based
on the backstory you've
written about yourself in
your brain. And it's
going to help tweak
the tone. And alignment
to fit your niche.
Again, don't blindly accept
what it gives you.
Think, edit it, make
it sound human. And
if your version hits
the key problems and
avoids the mistakes, you
don't have to use
the AI as you
can stick with it.
Now, please do not
monkey brain this.
If the AI version
is better, that's absolutely
great, but present it
out loud. I mean,
it doesn't sound like
you. Edit so it
sounds like you. Don't
just copy and paste
it and be lazy
and be like, that'll
do. Option two, you
just let the AI
draft for you. So
if you want to
go fast, do this.
Open intro bot and
say, here's my title.
Write the title. Can
you write me an
intro? It'll give you
three versions. Then just
pick the one you
like. Run it through
guardrails for more feedback.
And then make small
edits to personalize it.
And that's it. Now,
I still write my
intros manually, but this
is a really fast
way to get you
over that initial kind
of like thinking hurdle.
You're like, how do
I start this thing?
And it's going to
help you stay short
and very clear and
focused. And some final
notes on writing intros
for members. If you
want feedback from us,
what you want to
do is you want
to put your intro
in a Google doc
and then make sure
the link is set
to anyone with the
link and comment. If
you forget, you're going
to get a message
from us saying, please
make this doc open
for access. And that's
going to waste a
lot of your time.
But also, please don't
paste five AI generated
intros that you just
slapped up as quick
and go, which one
is it? Which one
is your best? Expecting
us to do all
the work, pick your
favorite, edit it and
submit one. If you
send too many, I'm
just going to say
pick one and we're
going to lose all
that time and go
through the process again.
The process is here
to make you better,
not just faster. And
it's not here to
enable you to be
lazy. So use the
tools, but do the
work and you will
be able to write
great intros without needing
much help from any
of us pretty flippant
soon.